A Guide to the Virginia Miscellany Papers, 1657-1931
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Virginia Miscellany Papers, 1657-1931
Library of Virginia
24715
1.365 cubic feet
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Purchased from the Parke Bernet Galleries, New York, New York, 23 October 1957
Scope and Content Information
Virginia miscellany, 1657-1931, contains letters and legal papers and is divided into two series. Series I contains letters, 1742-1931. Series II contains legal papers, 1657-1862.
Series I contains letters, 1742-1931, concerning business, legal matters, politics, education, commerce, military matters, religion, and foreign relations. Letters include correspondence between Moses S. Little of Boston, Massachusetts, and New York, New York, and Christopher Fry of Norfolk, Virginia, concerning commerce and shipping; John Wickham of Richmond, Virginia, and Thomas Swann of Alexandria, Virginia, regarding legal matters; Nicholas P. Trist and Henry Clay concerning employment for Trist in the State Department; and from Richard Channing Moore to prospective ministers for the Episcopalian Church in Virginia. Other correspondents include James Wood, Littleton Waller Tazewell, Nathaniel Macon, Edmund Randolph, Henry St. George Tucker, Chapman Johnson, Samuel C. Armstrong, and Francis P. Gaines. Series also includes a sermon written by Reverend James Muir of Alexandria, Virginia.
Series II contains legal papers, 1657-1862, consisting of: accounts, advertisements, agreements, bills of exchange, bills of sale, bonds, certificates, commissions, declarations, deeds, depositions, executions, indictments, inventories, judicial records, land grants, letters of administration, lists, lottery tickets, memorandums, notes, notices, petitions, pleas, powers of attorney, promissory notes, protests, receipts, resolutions, statements, summonses, warrants, wills, and writs. Deeds, land grants, and wills are from (Old) Rappahannock, Essex, Westmoreland, Prince William, King William, King and Queen, and Frederick Counties, and Winchester, Virginia. Bills, receipts, bonds, judicial records, and other legal papers are from all of Virginia, but mainly Frederick County. Check item inventory for list of individual items.
Arrangement
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically within each series.
Organization
Organized into two series: Series I: Letters, 1742-1931. Series II: Legal Papers, 1657-1862.
Contents List
- Letters, 1742-1931 (Box 1)
  - Letters, n.d., 1742-1779 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Letter, n.d., Moses S. Little to an unknown recipient., 3 p., incomplete.
    - Letter, n.d., Andrew Stevenson to Anthony Robinson., 1 leaf.
    - Letter fragment, n.d., from an unknown correspondent to John Page, Congressman from Virginia, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania., 1 leaf.
    - Letter, 1 November 1742, William Stone, Opecan [Opequan, Frederick County, Virginia], to Adam Reed, merchant at Falmouth, [Stafford County, Virginia]., 1 leaf.
    - Letter, 11 [October?] 1746, Thomas Rutherford to Gerrard Alexander, Fairfax County, [Virginia]., 1 leaf.
    - Letter, 31 October 1757, Jarvis Hougham to Mr. West, attorney-at-law. This is also item number 134 under the legal papers series., 1 leaf.
    - Memorandum, ca. 1774, re: the treatment of the American colonies by Great Britain., 3 p., also typescript copy, 2 leaves.
    - Letter, 31 August 1775, John Norton and Sons, London, [England], to Baker Perkins, Williamsburg, [Virginia]., 2 leaves.
    - Letter, 5 March 1778, Isaac Smith, Alexandria, [Virginia], to an unknown recipient., 1 leaf.
    - Letter, 5 October 1779, James Wood to Captain Joseph Swearingen, Berkeley County, [(West) Virginia]., 1 leaf.
  - Letters, 1780-1794 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Letter, 21 April 1780, John P. Posey, New Kent County, [Virginia], to John P. Custis. Copy of letter made 14 June 1790., 2 p.
    - Letter, 20 April 1781, John Brown, Botetourt [County, Virginia], to William Cabell, Amherst [County, Virginia]., 2 p.
    - Letter, 15 July 1787, Samuel Meredith, Cumberland County, [Virginia], to William Giles., 1 leaf.
    - Letter, 12 August 1790, Edmund Randolph, New York, to Beverley Randolph, Governor of Virginia, Richmond, [Virginia]., 1 leaf.
    - Letter, 14 June 1791, Philip Lee to John Smith, Frederick County., 1 leaf.
    - Letter, 7 July 1791, Charles Lee, Alexandria, to Colonel John Smith, Winchester, [Virginia]., 1 leaf.
    - Letter, 18 January 1798, J. Holker to Bataille Muse., 1 leaf.
    - Letter, 15 October 1793, J. Holker to Robert White., 1 leaf.
    - Letter, 1794, G. W. Howell to Governor Henry Lee, marked private., 1 leaf.
    - Letter, J. Holker to Bataille Muse., 2 p.
  - Letters, 1794-1799 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Letter, 3 March 1794, William Ball, Winchester, to the Clerk of the Frederick County Court., 1 leaf.
    - Letter, 25 April 1794, G. W. Howell, Philadelphia, [Pennsylvania], to Governor Henry Lee., 4 p.
    - Sermon, 22 August 1794, on Ephesians 2:12, by the Reverend James Muir, Alexandria., 20 p.
    - letter, 18 April 1795, Alexander White, Winchester, to General Isaac Zane., 1 leaf.
    - Letter, 25 May 1797, John Harvie, Richmond, [Virginia], to Arthur Lee, Commissioner of the Treasury, New York., 2 p.
    - Letter, 10 June 1797 Benedict Crump to Mr. Edmundson, tavern-keeper, Winchester., 1 leaf.
    - Letter, 13 July 1798, Robert Gamble to an unknown recipient., 2 p.
    - Letter, 12 October 1798, E. Langham, Shepherdstown, [Jefferson County, (West) Virginia], to [William] Davidson., 2 p.
    - Letter, 30 October 1798, E. Langham to William Davidson, Winchester., 2 p.
    - Letter, 3 January 1799 Josias Clapham to Samuel Clapham, General Assembly, Richmond., 2 p.
  - Letters, 1803-1817 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Letter, 1 May 1803, Isaac Williamson to Judge Morris., 1 leaf.
    - Letter, 10 October 1804, Fulwar Skipwith, Paris, [France], to Robert R. Livingston, Minister Plenipotentiary of the United States, Paris., 1 leaf.
    - Letter, 17 December 1804, John Wickham, Richmond, to Thomas Swann., 2 p.
    - Postscript to a letter, 15 May 1805, John Wickham, Richmond, to an unknown correspondent., 1 leaf.
    - Letter, 3 January 1807, W. Tebbs, Stratford, [Westmoreland County, Virginia], to an unknown recipient., 2 p.
    - Letter, 14 November 1811, George Poindexter, Washington, to Captain Edmund Pendleton Gaines, Fort Stoddart, Mississippi Territory., 3 p.
    - Letter, 26 January 1813 Henry St. George Tucker, Winchester, to an unknown recipient., 2 p.
    - Letter, 11 February 1813, Jacob Little, New York, to Messrs. Christopher Fry and E. Lee, merchants, Norfolk, [Virginia]., 1 leaf.
    - Letter, 26 July 1813, Jacob Little, Newbury Port, [Massachusetts], to Christopher Fry, Norfolk., 3 p.
    - Letter, 15 January 1817, Moses S. Little, Boston, [Massachusetts], to Christopher Fry, Norfolk, Virginia., 1 leaf.
  - Letters, 1817-1819 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Letter, 25 October 1817, Moses S. Little, New York, to Christopher Fry, Norfolk. Postscript from Jacob Little., 3 p.
    - Letter, 4 November 1817, Moses S. Little, New York, to Christopher Fry, Norfolk., 1 leaf.
    - Letter, 24 November 1817, Moses S. Little, New York, to Christopher Fry, Norfolk., 2 p.
    - Letter, 29 November 1817, Moses S. Little, Boston, [Massachusetts], to Christopher Fry., 4 p.
    - Letter, 29 January 1818, Moses S. Little, New York, to Christopher Fry, Norfolk., 2 p.
    - Letter, 28 May 1818, C.C., Philadelphia, to Mrs. Sarah Fry, Washington., 3 p.
    - Letter, 27 October 1818, John Wickham, Richmond, to Thomas Swann., 1 leaf.
    - Letter, 15 May 1819, John Wickham, Richmond, to Thomas Swann, Alexandria., 1 leaf.
    - Letter, 17 May 1819, Moses S. Little, New York, to Christopher Fry, Norfolk., 4 p.
    - Letter, 16 August 1819, Moses S. Little, New York, to Christopher Fry, Norfolk., 2 p.
  - Letters, n.d., 1819-1825 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Letter, 1 December 1819, Richard Channing Moore, Richmond, to the Reverend Alexander V. Griswold, Bristol, Rhode Island., 2 p.
    - Letter, 11 December 1819, Richard Channing Moore, Richmond, to an unknown recipient., 1 leaf.
    - Letter, 8 April 1820, G[eorge?] Mason, near Aquia, [Stafford County], to Clerk of the Superior Court of Law for Loudoun County, Leesburg, [Virginia]., 1 leaf.
    - Letter, 26 April 1820, Moses S. Little, Richmond, to Christopher Fry, Norfolk., 3 p.
    - Letter, 9 May 1820, Moses S. Little, Ricmond, to Christopher Fry., 1 leaf.
    - Letter, 10 May 1820, Moses S. Little, Richmond, to Christopher Fry, Norfolk., 1 leaf.
    - Letter, 24 January 1821, Richard H. Lee to an unknown recipient., 1 leaf.
    - Letter, 28 June 1821, W. Clarke, Staunton, [Virginia], to Peter Hagner., 2 p.
    - Letter, 28 February 1822, Hugh Nelson to an unknown recipient., 1 leaf.
    - Letter, 16 January [1825], Hezekiah Niles to William Niles., 1 leaf.
  - Letters, 1825-1840 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Letter, 1 March 1825, Chapman Johnson, Richmond, to John Randolph, Washington., 2 p.
    - Letter, 11 October 1828, Littleton Waller Tazewell, Norfolk, to Henry Fry, New York., 1 leaf.
    - Note, 24 October 1828, N. P. T. [Nicholas P. Trist], Monticello, to Henry Clay., 1 leaf, draft.
    - Letter, 8 November 1828, Nicholas P. Trist, Monticello, to Henry Clay., 1 leaf, draft.
    - Invitation, December 1828, Mr. and Mrs. Henry Clay to Nicholas P. Trist., 1 leaf.
    - Letter, 19 July 1834, A. Pomar, Norfolk, to Colonel Loammi Baldwin, Charleston [Charlestown], Massachusetts., 1 leaf.
    - Letter, 22 July 1835, Littleton Waller Tazewell, Richmond, to Erasmus Kennon et. al., Boydton, [Mecklenburg County, Virginia]., 1 leaf.
    - Letter, 26 June 1836, Nathaniel Macon, Buck Spring, [North Carolina], to an unknown recipient., 1 leaf.
    - Letter, 23 June 1838, John Snider, Grandville, Monongalia County, [(West) Virginia], to Albert A. Bailey, New Providence, Clarke County, Indiana., 2 p.
    - Letter, 20 July 1840, Thomas Crawford, Florence, [Italy], to George W. Greene, Rome, [Italy]., 3 p.
  - Letters, 1841-1931 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Note, 4 October 1841, Littleton Waller Tazewell, Norfolk, to an unknown recipient., 1 leaf.
    - Letter, 19 April 1851, Benjamin I. Crew, Philadelphia, to Aaron H. Griffith, Winchester, Virginia., 1 leaf.
    - Letter, 13 January [1871?] Samuel Chapman Armstrong, Hampton Normal and Agricultural Institute, Hampton, [Virginia], to an unknown recipient., 1 leaf.
    - Letter, 22 October 1889, Fitzhugh Lee, Richmond, to Major William H. Palmer[?]., 3 p.
    - Letter, 11 September 1892, Samuel Chapman Armstrong, Hampton Normal and Agricultural Institute, Hampton, to an unknown recipient., 1 leaf.
    - Letter, 9 January 1931, Francis P. Gaines, President, Washinton and Lee University, Lexington, [Virginia], to James B. Stewart, New York., 1 leaf, typewritten.
- Legal papers, 1657-1862 (Box 1-2)
  - Legal Papers, n.d., 1780 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - List of jurors, n.d., for Nathaniel Pendleton v. Williams., 1 leaf.
    - List, n.d., of militia officers recommended in the 1st Battalion of the 57th Regiment., 1 leaf.
    - Receipt, n.d., John M. Gilmour to Richard Lee Galloway., 1 leaf.
    - Statement, n.d., of Francis Whiting, attorney for the defense in Web, assignee, v. Washington., 1 leaf.
    - Note, n.d., Elizabeth Randolph to Messrs. Cohen and Isaacs., 1 leaf.
    - Exception, n.d., John Cordell v. Robert White., 1 leaf.
    - Plea, n.d., declaration of Bushrod Washington Corbin Washington, executors of John A. Washington in Washington v. Simon Crye McMahon and Fielding Lewis., 1 leaf.
    - Inventory, n.d., John Van Kluik's property., 15 p.
    - Declaration, n.d., Robert C. Burwell, assignee of Harfield Timberlake, complaining of Warner Washington, Frederick County., 1 leaf.
    - Blank certificate, 25 July 1780, Commonwealth of Virginia indebted to an unknown individual, no. 1207., 1 leaf.
  - Legal Papers, n.d., 1657-1681 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Memorandum, n.d., Thomas McGuire to Captain Christopher Gist., 1 leaf.
    - Paper, n.d., concerning action of Rust v. Rust., 1 leaf.
    - Paper, n.d., concerning the bond of Samuel Martin to Samuel G[unknown] and John [unknown]., 1 leaf.
    - Fragment, n.d., bearing the signature of [Thomas?] Swearingen., 1 leaf.
    - Fragment, n.d., unidentified., 1 leaf.
    - Land grant, 1 May 1657, for 1000 acres on the south side of the Rappahannock River to William White., 1 leaf, copy.
    - Land grant, 26 March 1666, for 6300 acres in (Old) Rappahannock County, [Virginia], to Robert Taliaferro and Lawrence Smith., 1 leaf, copy.
    - Land grant, 8 May 1674, for 3000 acres in (Old) Rappahannock County to George Morris., 2 pages, copy.
    - Land grant, 15 June 1675, for 4763 acres in (Old) Rappahannock County to Enock Doughty., 2 pages, copy.
    - Deed, 20 June 1681, for 180 acres in Westmoreland County, [Virginia], from Richard Norrill and Jane Norrill, both of Plymouth, Devonshire, England, through their attorney Malachy Peale, to John Blagdon of Westmoreland County. Recorded in Westmoreland County 3 August 1681. No recorded copy known to exist., 1 leaf.
  - Legal Papers, 1683-1731 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Land grant, 23 October 1690, for 500 acres in (Old) Rappahannock County to William Bendry., 1 leaf, copy.
    - Land grant, 16 April 1683, for 500 acres in New Kent and (Old) Rappahannock Counties to George Morris., 2 p. copy.
    - Land grant, 26 October 1694, for 720 acres in the freshes between the Rappahannock and Mattapony [Mattaponi] Rivers to Captain Richard Hale of Essex County, [Virginia]., 1 leaf, copy.
    - Land grant, 23 October 1703, for 500 acres in King William County, [Virginia], to John Baker., 1 leaf, copy.
    - Land grant, 26 April 1704, for 650 acres in Essex County to Robert Brooke., 1 leaf, copy.
    - Will, 17 January 1708, of Richard Stokes of Essex County. Recorded in Essex County 13 September 1711., 2 p.
    - Deed, 28 July 1712, from William Stokes to Arthur Mackdonel. Date is recordation date in Essex County., 2 p., incomplete.
    - Will, 15 October 1712, of Henry Newton of Essex County. Recorded in Essex County 11 March 1713., 2 p.
    - Deed, 10 December 1713, for 150 acres in Essex County from John Smith of Essex County to Ephraim Paget and his wife Mary of Essex County. Recorded in Essex County 9 April 1714., 1 leaf.
    - Will, 26 February 1730, of Henry Ashton of Westmoreland County. Probated in Westmoreland County 24 November 1731., 11 p.
  - Legal Papers, 1734-1744 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Account, 10 April 1734, Jones Lum to John Kankey., 1 leaf.
    - Account, 1738-1739, Peter Woolf to Charles Carter., 1 leaf.
    - Deed, 1 September 1741, for 447 acres in Prince William County, [Virginia], from Clement Nicholson of the Kingdom of Great Britain, mariner, to Harry Turner of King George County, [Virginia]. Recorded in Prince William County, [Virginia], 22 March 1741/42., 1 leaf.
    - Account, October 1741-October 1742, Ulrich Pooker to an unknown individual., 1 leaf.
    - Account, 1743, Joseph Robins to John Lee., 1 leaf.
    - Promissory note, 10 January 1743, from Richard Cronk of Frederick County, [Virginia], to Charles Dick, merchant, Frederick County., 1 leaf.
    - Bond, 19 December 1743, John Nelans of Frederick County to Philip Lightfoot of Yorktown, [Virginia]., 1 leaf.
    - Bond, 26 September 1743, Benjamin Miller of Lancaster County, [Virginia], and George Parker, Jr., of Prince George County, [Virginia], to William Baldwin of Orange County, [Virginia]., 2 p.
    - Account, 1744, Jonathan Seaman to Secretary [Thomas] Nelson., 1 leaf.
    - Will, 1744, of William Aylett of Westmoreland County., 4 p., incomplete.
  - Legal Papers, 1744-1746 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Execution, 9 September 1744, to the sheriff of King George County to summon Henry Meecham in the acton of Charles Carter v. Peter Woolf., 1 leaf.
    - Promissory note, 24 November 1744, from Hugh Heartley of Frederick County to Ralph Falkner and John Muschett, merchants, Charles County, Maryland., 1 leaf.
    - Bill of exchange, 18 March 1745, Stephen Rawlings to William Reynolds., 1 leaf.
    - Promissory note, 21 June 1745, from Jacob Hopeman of Frederick County to Adam Reid of King George County., 1 leaf.
    - Suit paper, 21 September 1745, from a court-martial, order against Captain Thomas Rutherford., 1 leaf.
    - Account, July 1744-October 1745, Daniel Hart to Charles Green., 1 leaf.
    - Account, 1746, William Mitchell, Jonathan Seaman, and John Woodson to Secretary [Thomas] Nelson., 1 leaf.
    - Bond, 4 June 1746, William Chapman and Solomon Hedges of Frederick County, to Joshua Way of Willington, New Castle County, Delaware., 1 leaf.
    - Suit paper, 20 June 1746, judgment of Augusta County Court in action of Andrew Reed v. Thomas Molfelt., l leaf, copy.
    - Protest, 14 August 1746, of Williams and Rockeliffe of London, merchants, to John Buchanan concerning the bill of exchange from Stephen Rawlings to John Buchanan, merchant in London, regarding William Reynolds., 1 leaf.
  - Legal Papers, 1747-1748 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Account, 1747, William Williams to Mr. Secretary [Thomas] Nelson., 2 p.
    - Account, 1747, William Mitchell, Jonathan Seaman, and John Woodson to Mr. Secretary [Thomas] Nelson., 1 leaf.
    - Account, 1747, William Green, Reader, to Vestrymen and Collector of Frederick Parish [Frederick County]., 1 leaf.
    - Account, 1744-1747, Dan Hart to Charles Green., 1 leaf.
    - Suit paper, 28 April 1747, judgment in the acton of John Dalton v. Thomas Chester and John Wile. Williamsburg General Court., 1 leaf, copy.
    - Receipt, 23 September 1747, J. Mercer to John Richards., 1 leaf.
    - Bond, 10 October 1747, John Wilcocks, carpenter of Frederick County, to Nathaniel Chapman of Stafford County., 1 leaf.
    - Account, July 1746-November 1747, Joseph Robbins to Alexander and Daniel Campbell., 1 leaf.
    - Promissory note, 29 December 1747, William Green of Frederick County to Matthew Hopkins of the province of Maryland., 2 p.
    - Account, October 1747-January 1748, Thomas Brown to an unknown individual., 2 p.
  - Legal Papers, 1748-1749 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Letter of administration, 5 April 1748, William Plumstead, Registrar General for the Probate of Wills and Granting Letters of Administration in and for the Province of Pennsylvania to Sophia Mayberry, widow and relict of Thomas Mayberry of Philadelphia County, [Pennsylvania]., 1 leaf.
    - Bond, 6 June 1748, Samuel Walker of Frederick County to William Hicks., 1 leaf.
    - Deed, 17 June 1748, for 790 acres in Frederick County from Robert Worthington of Frederick County to Lawrence Washington of Fairfax County, [Virginia]. Recorded in Frederick County 3 August 1748., 3 p.
    - Promissory note, 18 July 1748, from Richard Sutherton of Frederick County to Alexander and Daniel Campbell., 2 p..
    - Receipt, 1 December 1748, Thomas Cresap to Joseph Volgamat for John English., 2 p.
    - Account, 1748-1749, Robert Marshall to Messrs. Maxwell, merchants in Britain., 1 leaf.
    - Bond, 12 January 1748/49, John Ross and William Watson of Frederick County to William and David McSwaine, merchants of Philadelphia., 1 leaf.
    - Promissory note, 7 February 1748/49, from John Neelans and Thomas Chester to James Wood or Marquis Calmes, executors of Daniel Hart, deceased., 1 leaf.
    - Account, 1748-1749, Andrew Campbell to William Green., 1 leaf.
    - Account, 1749, William Mitchell, Jonathan Seaman, and John Woodson to Mr. Secretary [Thomas] Nelson., 1 leaf.
  - Legal Papers, 1749-1751 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Promissory note, 23 September 1749, from Vincent Tapp of Fairfax County to Daniel and Alexander Campbell., 2 p.
    - Account, 1749-1750, John Hampton to William Cocker., 1 leaf.
    - Account, 1750, Meredith Helmes to Secretary [Thomas] Nelson., 2 p.
    - Promissory note, 11 August 1750, from James Russell to Messrs. Trent and Croghan., 2 p.
    - Promissory note, 11 August 1750, from Owen Wingfield of Stafford County to David Ross or Charles Hammond., 2 p.
    - Account, 6 October 1750, Remembrance Williams to James Dickson., 1 leaf.
    - Account, 17 November 1750, Peter Burr to William Ramsay., 1 leaf.
    - Promissory note, 29 November 1750, from Robert Mosley, planter, King George County, to Cochran and Company, merchants in Glasgow, [Scotland]., 2 p.
    - Account, January 1748/49-May 1751, John Ashbie to Andrew Cochran and Company., 2 p.
    - Account, September 1751, Matthew Brooks to William Copland., 2 p.
  - Legal Papers, 1751-1752 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Account, 8 October 1751-1 November 1751, Jerom Williams to an unidentified individual., 2 p.
    - Account, 1752, John Sherman to an unidentified individual., 1 leaf.
    - Account, 1752, David Wood to James Coddy., 1 leaf.
    - Account, 1752, Hezekiah Clarke to Secretary [Thomas] Nelson., 1 leaf.
    - Account, 1750-1752, William Green to John Page., 1 leaf.
    - Account, 20 January 1752, William Halling to James Spurr., 1 leaf.
    - Promissory note, 10 April 1752, from William Quinton of Frederick County to John Peill and others., 1 leaf.
    - Bond, 2 June 1752, Charles Worrell of King George County to Andrew Ross., 2 p.
    - Bond, 2 June 1752, Charles Worrell to Charles Carter. Includes note, 7 June 1752, Charles Carter to [Andrew?] Ross., 2 p.
    - Bill of Sale, 11 June 1752, for 150 acres of land in Prince William County from Shaddrack Parlour of Augusta County, [Virginia] to Joseph Neavill of Prince William County., 1 leaf.
  - Legal Papers, 1752-1753 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Bond, 13 June 1752, Thomas Graham of Fairfax County to William Bayly of Prince William County., 1 leaf.
    - Account, 15 June 1752, Andrew Frazer Shenandoah, [Virginia], to Messrs. Maxwell, merchants in Britain, their store at Aquia [Stafford County]., 2 p.
    - Account, June 1752, Hugh McHenry to John Martin., 1 leaf.
    - Account, May-November 1752, John Sturman to John Madison., 1 leaf.
    - Account, October 1752, Robert Burgess to C. Wagener., 1 leaf.
    - Account, 23 October 1752, William Potter to Robert and Edward Maxwell., 2 p.
    - Account, 2 November 1752, Philip Remack to David Short., 1 leaf.
    - Account, 1753, Edward Snickers to Richard Simpson., 1 leaf.
    - Account, 1753, Andrew Campbell to Secretary [Thomas] Nelson., 1 leaf.
    - Account, 1753, Andrew Campbell and George Johnston to Secretary [Thomas] Nelson., 1 leaf.
  - Legal Papers, 1753-1754 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Account, 1753, Andrew Campbell, James McCracken, and Robert Paul to Secretary [Thomas] Nelson., 1 leaf.
    - Account, 1753, Richard Sherman, John Matthews, James Taft, Joseph Wood, and Hugh Fox to Secretary [Thomas] Nelson., 1 leaf.
    - Account, 1753, John Bryant to John Champe., 1 leaf.
    - Account, August 1752-April 1753. John Briscoe to Thomas Machen., 1 leaf.
    - Account, 29 October 1753, Michael Hoiler to Samuel Knox., 2 p.
    - Promissory note, 10 November 1753, from Reuben Rutherford to Hugh West., 1 leaf, copy.
    - Promissory note, 26 November 1753, from James McKay of Augusta County to Martin Funk., 2 p., copy.
    - Account, December 1752-December 1754, Richard Paris to an unknown individual., 1 leaf.
    - Account, 1754, Charles Aquilla Dorsey to William Kitchen., 1 leaf.
    - Account, 1754, Richard Sherman, John Matthews, Richard Taft, and John Nealand to Secretary [Thomas] Nelson., 1 leaf.
  - Legal Papers, 1754-1755 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Account, 1754, Richard Sherman, John Matthews, James Taft, Joseph Wood, and Hugh Fox to Secretary [Thomas] Nelson., 1 leaf.
    - Account, 1754, Richard Sherman to Secretary [Thomas] Nelson., 1 leaf.
    - Bond, 9 May 1754, Leonard Helm of Frederick County to Andrew Cochran, Esq., and Company, merchants in Glasgow., 2 p.
    - Promissory note, 22 June 1754, from Charles Aquil[l]a Dorsey of Fairfax [County] to William Scott., 1 leaf.